Guide to the Mabel Dodge Luhan Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1905-1954; Series I; 17.31; (42 boxes)
  - GENERAL CORRESPONDENCE
    - Sinclair, Upton, 1914-53, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 907)
    - Sisters of the Holy Family of Nazareth, 1936-45, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 908-909)
      Includes letter from MDL and carbon of letter to Sisters from Franklin D. Roosevelt
    - Sloane, Eric, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 910)
    - Sloane, May E., 1936 (Box 31, Folder 911)
    - Smith, Truman, 1947 (Box 31, Folder 912)
    - Snow, Edith Abercrombie, 1933 Sep 1 (Box 31, Folder 913)
    - Snow, Edward O., 1917 (Box 31, Folder 914)
    - Soskin, William, 1936-37 (Box 31, Folder 915)
    - Southwest Review, 1946 Jun 17 (Box 31, Folder 916)
    - Speiser, Maurice J. (Maurice Joseph), 1946 Nov 11 (Box 31, Folder 917)
    - Spender, Stephen, 1950, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 918)
    - Sprague, Alice, 1937-43, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 919)
    - Sprague, Elfleda, 1938-46, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 920-922)
    - Stafford, Jean, 1952, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 923)
    - Stavereu, Herbert, 1942 (Box 32, Folder 924)
    - Steffens, Lincoln, 1913-36 (Box 32, Folder 925)
      Includes copies
    - Stein, Fred M., 1947-48 (Box 32, Folder 926)
    - Stein, Gertrude, 1911-22, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 927-930)
      Includes carbon
    - Stein, Leo (1872-1947), 1911-37, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 931-936)
    - Stein, Nina
      Includes letters to Stein from "R. Littell" of The New Republic
    - Sterne, Maurice, 1915-16 (Box 32, Folder 937-945)
      See also: Writings, Autobiographical Writings, "Letters from Hutchins & Neith Hapgood..." (leaf 77), Box 51, folder 1404
    - Sterne, Maurice, 1917-53, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 946-954)
    - Sterne, Maurice, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 955)
    - Stieglitz, Alfred, 1913-35, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 956-960)
    - Stokowska, Evangeline, 1932-41, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 961)
    - Stokowski, Leopold, 1931-48, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 962-965)
    - Stoller, Leo, 1946 Apr 26 (Box 33, Folder 966)
    - Street, Julian, 1913 May 27 (Box 33, Folder 967)
    - Strong, Anna Louise, 1925 (Box 33, Folder 968)
      Includes manuscript "Back from our Children's Colony"
    - Stuart, John
    - Sturges, Catherine Vesta, 1933-36 (Box 33, Folder 969)
      Includes carbon of letter from Sturges to John Collier
    - Sullivan, Noël, 1933-37 (Box 34, Folder 970)
    - Survey Graphic, 1922, 1931 (Box 34, Folder 971)
    - Swaine, Ruth, 1933-54, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 972)
    - Swazo, Benito, 1944-45 (Box 34, Folder 973)
    - "T" General, 1915-54, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 974-977)
      Includes letter from MDL to "Children of Dr. Thorne"
    - Tannenbaum, Frank, 1915-32 (Box 34, Folder 978)
    - Tant, Charles, 1939-46 (Box 34, Folder 979)
    - Taylor, Clara Sidney, 1918-20, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 980-983)
      Includes letter from MDL and carbon of letter from Bentano's to CST
    - Taylor, Henry F., n.d. (Box 34, Folder 984)
    - Taylor, Livingston N., 1936-39 (Box 34, Folder 985)
    - Teall, Dorothy, 1932 Dec 15 (Box 34, Folder 986)
    - Tedlock, E. W. (Ernest Warnock), 1944 Aug 2 (Box 34, Folder 987)
    - Teris, Lloyd, 1935, 1946 (Box 34, Folder 988)
    - Theatre Arts Monthly, 1924 Feb 22 (Box 34, Folder 989)
    - Thomas, Elmer
    - Thompson, Clarence, 1932, 1942 (Box 34, Folder 990)
    - Thursby, Alice, 1932-44, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 991)
      See also: Writings, Autobiographical Writings, "Duncan Letters 1918, Eve and School 1920-1928" (leaves 278-300), Box 46, folder 1386
    - Time, 1946 Jul 1 (Box 34, Folder 992)
    - Toomer, Jean, 1925-37, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 993-994)
    - Toor, Frances, 1932-33 (Box 34, Folder 995)
    - Torrence, Olivia, 1925-29, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 996)
    - Torrence, Ridgely, 1915-36, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 997)
    - Town & Country, 1937-46, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 998)
    - Tree, Iris, 1930 (Box 34, Folder 999)
    - Tregor, Nison, 1941 May 18 (Box 34, Folder 1000)
    - Twilight Sleep Association, 1915, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 1001)
    - "U" General, 1945, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 1002)
    - Ufer, Mary M., 1923-27, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 1003)
    - United States. Bureau of Immigration, 1915-17 (Box 34, Folder 1004)
    - United States. Dept. of Justice, 1945 May 8 (Box 34, Folder 1005)
    - United States. Indian Arts and Crafts Board, 1938 Dec 19 (Box 34, Folder 1006)
    - United States. Office for Emergency Management, 1943 Dec 31 (Box 34, Folder 1007)
    - United States. Office of Indian Affairs, 1922-47 (Box 34, Folder 1008)
      Includes letters from MDL and John Collier
      See also: Evans, John, Boxes 12-14, folders 324-368
    - United States. Post Office Dept., 1945-46 (Box 34, Folder 1009)
    - Unity School of Christianity, 1914-16 (Box 34, Folder 1010)
    - University of New Mexico, 1942-52 (Box 35, Folder 1011)
    - University of New Mexico Press, 1953 Jun 4 (Box 35, Folder 1012)
    - Untermeyer, Minnie, 1916, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1013)
    - "V" General, 1914-53, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1014-1015)
    - Van Doren, Irita, 1937 Mar 19 (Box 35, Folder 1016)
    - Van Leuven, "Dutchee", 1914-16, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1017)
    - [Van Maltzen, Hanni?], 1934-35 (Box 35, Folder 1018)
    - Van Maltzen, "Teddy", 1934-36 (Box 35, Folder 1019)
    - Van Vechten, Carl, 1912-52 (Box 35, Folder 1020-1028)
      Includes note from MDL on letter from Cosmopolitan, dated 1938, and photographs
    - Van Vechten, Carl, 1952-54, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 1029-1033)
    - Van Vechten, Duane, 1933-49 (Box 36, Folder 1034)
    - Van Vechten, Fania Marinoff, 1913-34 (Box 36, Folder 1035)
    - Vanderbilt, Ollie, 1942-52, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 1036-1037)
    - Vanity Fair, 1925 (Box 36, Folder 1038)
    - Varèse, Edgard, 1926 Sep 16 (Box 36, Folder 1039)
    - Vidal, Gore, 1952 (Box 36, Folder 1040)
    - Viking Press, 1936 Mar 20 (Box 36, Folder 1041)
    - Villa, José García, 1932 (Box 36, Folder 1042)
    - Vinal, Harold, 1925 Nov 3 (Box 36, Folder 1043)
    - Von Heiroth, Mascha, 1929-34 (Box 36, Folder 1044)
    - Von Miklos, Josephine, 1930, 1940 (Box 36, Folder 1045)
    - Vorse, Mary Heaton, 1929, 1935 (Box 36, Folder 1046)
    - "W" General, 1914-54, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 1047-1054)
    - Wagstaff, Blanche "Shumacher"
      See: Scrapbooks, "Lawrence," Box 87, folder 2256
    - Wallace, Lew Barrington, 1937, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 1055)
    - Ward, Winifred, 1917 May 5 (Box 36, Folder 1056)
    - [Warner?], Edith, 1935 Jul 12 (Box 36, Folder 1057)
    - Warren, Robert Penn
      See: Donahoe, Edward, Boxes 8-9, folders 242-262
    - Waters, Frank, 1938-43 (Box 37, Folder 1058-1066)
      Includes letters from MDL and carbon of letter from Waters to New Mexico Quarterly
      See also: Waters, "Janey," Box 37, folders 1079-1081
    - Waters, Frank, 1943-53, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 1067-1075)
    - Waters, Frank, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 1076-1078)
    - Waters, "Janey", 1954, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 1079-1081)
      Includes note from Frank Waters
    - Watts, Diana
      See: Writings, Autobiographical Writings, "Letters of John and Lucy Collier 1913-1917" (leaves 364-367), Box 51, folder 1405
    - Weber, Max, 1913 (Box 38, Folder 1082)
    - Weeks, Mabel Foote, 1916-36, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 1083-1084)
    - Wells, Cady, 1934-54, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 1085)
      Includes note from MDL and enclosures
    - Wells, Riki, 1934 Mar 27 (Box 38, Folder 1086)
    - West, Isabelle, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 1087)
    - Weston, Edward, 1933-34, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 1088)
    - [White?], Amelia Elizabeth, 1922 Sep 1 (Box 38, Folder 1089)
    - Whiting, Elizabeth, 1937 Sep 20 (Box 38, Folder 1090)
    - Wickes, Frances G., 1928-29, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 1091)
    - Wilcox, Ansley, 1916 Dec 7 (Box 38, Folder 1092)
    - Wilczynski, Kaete, 1937 (Box 38, Folder 1093)
    - Wilder, Isabel, 1938-51, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 1094)
    - Wilder, Thornton, 1933-48, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 1095-1097)
    - William Morrow and Company, 1934-36 (Box 38, Folder 1098)
    - Williams, Louise (cousin), 1929 Jul 2 (Box 38, Folder 1099)
    - Wolff, Adolf, 1914 Nov 13 (Box 38, Folder 1100)
    - Woman's Municipal League (New York, N.Y.), 1917 May 4 (Box 38, Folder 1101)
    - Woman's Peace Party, 1915 (Box 38, Folder 1102)
      See also: Evans, Elizabeth Glendower, Box 11, folder 321
    - Women's Trade Union League of New York, 1935 Oct 21 (Box 38, Folder 1103)
    - Woolston, Florence, 1917 Oct 29 (Box 38, Folder 1104)
    - Wright, Cedric, 1938 Feb 2 (Box 38, Folder 1105)
    - Wright, Willard Huntington, 1916 Apr 6 (Box 38, Folder 1106)
    - "Y" General, 1914-44, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 1107)
    - Yale University, 1920 Dec 15 (Box 38, Folder 1108)
    - Yale University. Library, 1949-51 (Box 38, Folder 1109)
    - Young, Ella, 1929-53, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 1110-1111)
    - Young, James W., 1925-48, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 1112)
    - Young-Hunter, Eve, 1922-53, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 1113-1116)
    - Young-Hunter, John, 1920-51, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 1117-1118)
    - Young-Hunter, Mary, 1921-28, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 1119)
    - "Z" General, 1922-50, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 1120)
    - Zigrosser, Carl, 1940, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 1121)
    - Unidentified
      - "A", 1916, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1122)
      - "B", 1914-49, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1123)
      - ----, Berthe
        See: Writings, Autobiographical Writings, "Letters from Hutchins &Neith Hapgood..." (leaves 235 and 297), Box 51, folder 1404
      - "C", 1953, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1124)
        Includes letter from Josephine W. Duveneck to "Mr. Goodrich"
      - "D", 1935-51, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1125)
      - "E", 1915-47, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1126)
      - ----, Elizabeth, 1915-27, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1127-1132)
      - ----, Elvira, 1943, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1133)
      - ----, Eva, 1917 (Box 39, Folder 1134)
      - "F", 1924, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1135)
      - "G", 1919, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1136)
      - "H", 1929, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1137)
      - ----, Hazel, 1915-49 (Box 39, Folder 1138)
      - "J", 1919-48, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1139)
      - ----, Jack, 1943, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1140)
      - "K", 1947-48 (Box 39, Folder 1141)
      - "L", 1912-38, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1142)
      - ----, [Lamiciso?], 1922-23, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1143)
      - ----, Lou, 1942, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1144)
      - "M", 1938-53, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1145)
      - ----, Marian, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1146)
      - ----, Mary, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1147)
      - "N", 1948 Jul 13 (Box 39, Folder 1148)
      - ----, Naomi, 1946-48, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1149)
      - ----, [Neysa?], n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1150)
        See also: Brill, A. A. (Abraham Arden), Box 4, folders 122-126
      - "O", n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1151)
      - "P", n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1152)
      - "R", 1947-50, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1153)
      - ----, Ruby, 1944 (Box 39, Folder 1154)
      - "S", 1916-46, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1155)
      - ----, "Sister", n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1156)
      - ----, "Sister" Beatrix
        See: Writings, Autobiographical Writings, "Letters of John and Lucy Collier 1913-1917" (leaves 108-125), Box 51, folder 1405
      - ----, "Sister" Teresita, 1935-38, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1157)
      - "T", 1937-46, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1158)
      - "V", n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1159)
      - "W", 1920 Jan 19 (Box 40, Folder 1160)
      - ----, [Yorba?], 1913, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1161)
    - Illegible signatures, 1914-54, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1162)
    - Unsigned, 1914-50, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1163)
    - Letters from MDL to unidentified recipients, 1913-14 (Box 40, Folder 1164)
    - Empty envelopes, 1951-54, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1165)
  - THIRD PARTY CORRESPONDENCE
    - To Bessie Beatty
      - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1945 (Box 40, Folder 1166)
    - To and from Dorothy Brett
      - Charles Scribner's Sons, 1930 Aug 15 (Box 40, Folder 1167)
      - Cristina, Maria C., 1930 Aug 15 (Box 40, Folder 1168)
      - Kiker, H[enry] A., 1935 Oct 28 (Box 40, Folder 1169)
      - Montague, "Mr.", 1928 Feb 24 (Box 40, Folder 1170)
      - Other correspondence (Box 40, Folder 1171)
    - To John Collier
      - Henderson, Alice Corbin, 1922-23 (Box 40, Folder 1172)
      - Waters, Frank, 1951 Nov 8 (Box 40, Folder 1173)
        Includes note by MDL and carbon
    - To and from Edwin Sherrill Dodge
      - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1913-36 (Box 40, Folder 1174)
    - To and from John Evans
      - Brett, Dorothy, 1935, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1175)
      - Clark, Rose, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1176)
      - Dodge, Edwin Sherrill, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1177)
      - Evans, Alice Henderson (Box 40, Folder 1178)
      - Evans, Nancy, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1179)
      - Evans, Natalie Sarah, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1180)
      - Montague, Sara Cook Ganson, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1181)
      - Reed, John, 1915 Jun 30 (Box 40, Folder 1182)
      - Sterne, Maurice, 1934 Jul 12 (Box 40, Folder 1183)
      - Unesco, 1947 Mar 6 (Box 40, Folder 1184)
      - Vanderberg, Arthur H., 1947 Mar 21 (Box 40, Folder 1185)
      - Other correspondence, 1916-47 (Box 40, Folder 1186)
    - To and from Manuel Gamio
      - Kellogg, Paul U., 1930 Nov 26 (Box 40, Folder 1187)
      - Other correspondence, 1930 Dec 9 (Box 40, Folder 1188)
    - To Hutchins Hapgood
      - Boyce, Neith, 1929 Jul (Box 40, Folder 1189)
      - Boyesen, Bayard, 1914 Apr 13 (Box 40, Folder 1190)
      - Collier, John
        See: Writings, Autobiographical Writings, "Letters of John and Lucy Collier 1913-1917" (leaves 9, 19 and 27), Box 51, folder 1405
      - The International, 1914 Jan 14 (Box 40, Folder 1191)
      - Reed, John, 1915 [Aug?] 31 (Box 40, Folder 1192)
    - To "Mrs." Hapgood
      - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1916, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1193)
    - To Alice Corbin Henderson
      - Johnson, Walter Willard (Spud), n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1194)
    - To and from Rebecca Salsbury James
      - Duell, Sloan & Pearce, 1947 Mar (Box 40, Folder 1195)
      - Hough, Henry, 1943 May (Box 40, Folder 1196)
        Includes "Transcript of the Meeting of the Taos Pueblo Indian Council"
      - Tant, Charles, 1946 Dec 20 (Box 40, Folder 1197)
    - To Una Jeffers
      - Evans, John, 1936 (Box 40, Folder 1198)
      - Hicks, Granville
      - Martin, Anne, 1930 Jun 23 (Box 40, Folder 1199)
      - Wood, Erskine, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1200)
      - Other correspondence, 1930, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1201)
    - To Walter Willard (Spud) Johnson
      - Presbyterian Church in the U.S.A. Board of National Missions, 1949 Jun 16 (Box 41, Folder 1202)
      - [Rauh?], Ida, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1203)
      - Other correspondence (Box 41, Folder 1204)
    - To and from Robert Edmond Jones
      - Draper, Muriel, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1205)
      - Hopkins, Emma Curtis, 1922, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1206)
      - Reed, John, 1915 Jun (Box 41, Folder 1207)
      - Other correspondence (Box 41, Folder 1208)
    - To Henry A. Kiker
      - Sage Books, 1948 Oct 22 (Box 41, Folder 1209)
      - Other correspondence, 1937, 1947 (Box 41, Folder 1210)
    - To and from Frieda Lawrence von Richthofen
      - Gallup, Donald, 1951 Nov 13 (Box 41, Folder 1211)
      - Martin, Dexter, 1951 Sep 10 (Box 41, Folder 1212)
      - Other correspondence, 1934-51, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1213)
    - To Tony Luhan
      - Angulo, Jaime de, 1924 (Box 41, Folder 1214)
      - Archuleto, Antonio, 1935, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1215)
      - Brett, Dorothy, [1936-37] (Box 41, Folder 1216)
      - Chávez, Dennis, 1937 May 25 (Box 41, Folder 1217)
      - Donahoe, Edward, 1952 Jan 24 (Box 41, Folder 1218)
      - Evans, John, 1921 (Box 41, Folder 1219)
      - James, Rebecca Salsbury, 1929 Sep 19 (Box 41, Folder 1220)
      - Johnson, Walter Willard (Spud), 1926 (Box 41, Folder 1221)
      - League of Nations, 1944 Jun 7 (Box 41, Folder 1222)
      - National Conference of Social Work, 1935 Dec 5 (Box 41, Folder 1223)
      - New Mexico Association on Indian Affairs, 1952 Sep 17 (Box 41, Folder 1224)
      - Parsons, Elsie Worthington Clews, 1932 Apr 11 (Box 41, Folder 1225)
      - Rogers, Millicent, 1947 Sep 11 (Box 41, Folder 1226)
      - Stieglitz, Alfred, 1940 Nov 24 (Box 41, Folder 1227)
      - Stokowska, Evangeline, 1933, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1228)
      - Stokowski, Leopold, 1921-24 (Box 41, Folder 1229)
      - Swazo, Benito, 1943 Dec 7 (Box 41, Folder 1230)
      - Taylor, Livingston N., 1946 Mar 22 (Box 41, Folder 1231)
      - Thursby, Alice, [ca. 1942], n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1232)
      - United States. Office of Indian Affairs, 1933-45 (Box 41, Folder 1233)
        Includes copy of letter from Jim L. Lujan
      - Vanderbilt, Ollie (Box 41, Folder 1234)
      - Other correspondence, 1924-47 (Box 41, Folder 1235)
    - To and from John Reed
      - Hapgood, Hutchins, 1915, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1236)
      - Hartley, Marsden, 1918 (Box 41, Folder 1237)
      - Hovey, Carl, 1915 May 24 (Box 41, Folder 1238)
      - Morristown School (Morristown, N. J.), 1914 Apr 8 (Box 41, Folder 1239)
    - To Lisa des Renaudes
      - Thursby, Alice, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1240)
      - Other correspondence, 1945 Feb 4 (Box 41, Folder 1241)
    - To and from Elfleda Sprague
      - Waters, Frank, 1944 Apr 14 (Box 41, Folder 1242)
      - Other correspondence, 1945 Dec 12 (Box 41, Folder 1243)
    - To Maurice Sterne
      - Birnbaum, Martin, 1917 Oct (Box 41, Folder 1244)
      - Evans, John, 1916 Oct 3 (Box 41, Folder 1245)
      - Hapgood, Hutchins
        See: Writings, Autobiographical Writings, "Letters from Hutchins & Neith Hapgood..." (leaf 77), Box 51, folder 1404
      - Pach, Walter, 1920 Jan 2 (Box 41, Folder 1246)
      - Pascin, Jules, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1247)
      - Other correspondence, 1917 Oct 17
    - To and from Alfred Stieglitz
      - Adams, Dabney M., 1942 Jul 2 (Box 41, Folder 1248)
      - Hartley, Marsden
        See: Writings, Autobiographical Writings, "Letters from Arthur Brisbane..." (leaves 132-139), Box 50, folder 1403
    - To and from Clara Sidney Taylor
      - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1919, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1249)
    - To Alice Thursby
      - Brisbane, Arthur, 1915-17 (Box 41, Folder 1250)
      - Van Vechten, Carl, 1920 Apr 15 (Box 41, Folder 1251)
      - Other correspondence (Box 41, Folder 1252)
    - To and from Frank Waters
      - Gilpin, Laura, 1950 Dec 31 (Box 41, Folder 1253)
      - New Mexico Quarterly, 1951 (Box 41, Folder 1254)
        Includes carbons of 3rd-party correspondence with "Spud" Johnson and O. E. Berninghaus
      - Other correspondence, 1950, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1255)
    - Other Third Party Correspondence
      - Archuleto, Antonio to Dr. Lewis, 1924 Jun 2[4?] (Box 41, Folder 1256)
      - Beckett, Luman to Leytton B. Buehler, 1934-35 (Box 41, Folder 1257)
      - Bing, Anna to Angelino Ravagli, 1946 Aug 14 (Box 41, Folder 1258)
      - Boyd, E. to Cady [Wells?], n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1259)
      - Bull, Nina to Frances Seidenstricker, 1914, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1260)
      - Cosmopolitan to Jane Hardy, 1935 (Box 41, Folder 1261)
      - Dell, Margery to unidentified, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1262)
      - Dreiser, Theodore to Finnish Relief Fund, 1940 Jan 9 (Box 41, Folder 1263)
      - Dunn, Charles Wesley to Pat Harrison, 1940 Jan 18 (Box 41, Folder 1264)
      - Ellis, Carolyne Crockett to The Masses, 1916 Aug 26 (Box 41, Folder 1265)
      - Eyre & Evers to "Miss Clark", 1933 Nov 21 (Box 41, Folder 1266)
      - Finnish Relief Fund to Theodore Dreiser, 1940 Feb 8 (Box 41, Folder 1267)
      - Francis, John A. to Sam A. Lewisohn, 1915 Apr 26 (Box 41, Folder 1268)
      - Harrington, M. Raymond to "Mr. Jones" (Box 41, Folder 1269)
      - Hartley, Marsden to Charles Demuth, [1913?] (Box 41, Folder 1270)
      - Henry George School of Social Science (New York, N.Y.) to unidentified, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1271)
      - Houghton Mifflin Company to Eva J. Dockery, 1919 Aug 13 (Box 42, Folder 1272)
      - Houghton Mifflin Company to Willard Hoagland, 1944 Aug 3 (Box 42, Folder 1273)
      - Janes, Robert William to Claire [Spencer?] and John [Evans?] (Box 42, Folder 1274)
      - Joseph F. Perry & Sons to Sam A. Lewisohn, 1915 Jan 24 (Box 42, Folder 1275)
      - Loy, Mina to Stephen Haweis, 1914 Mar [22?] (Box 42, Folder 1276)
      - McCutcheon, John T. to Elizabeth Shepley Sergeant, 1923 (Box 42, Folder 1277)
      - Marchand, Mariette to New York World Telegram, 1940 Feb 15 (Box 42, Folder 1278)
      - Martinez, Albert to Dennis Chávez, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1279)
      - Martinez, Albert to The Santa Fe New Mexican, 1936 Jul 17 (Box 42, Folder 1280)
      - Montague, Joseph E. to Anglo-American Mill Company, 1925 May (Box 42, Folder 1281)
      - Montague, Sara Cook Ganson to Mrs. Morris Cohn, 1927 Sep 19 (Box 42, Folder 1282)
      - M., H. K. to "Walter", 1914 Apr 16 (Box 42, Folder 1283)
      - Nightingale, Elizabeth to Mrs. Fish, 1952 May 20 (Box 42, Folder 1284)
      - Owings, Edna M. to "Una", n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1285)
      - Redwing, Lilia to Taos District Attorney, 1925 Jul 25 (Box 42, Folder 1286)
      - Schlippenbach, Baron von to George Baker, 1914 Mar 7 (Box 42, Folder 1287)
      - Sickles, [Daniel Edgar?] to "Sheriff [Warburger?], 1913 May 21 (Box 42, Folder 1288)
      - Sinclair, Upton to "Comrade" Sheldon, 1914 Jun 3 (Box 42, Folder 1289)
      - Society of the Lying-In Hospital to Witter Bynner, 1923 Aug 9 (Box 42, Folder 1290)
      - Stein, Leo to D. H. Lawrence, 1921 Nov 9 (Box 42, Folder 1291)
      - Stockton, Miriam to [Mr. Jones?], 1928 (Box 42, Folder 1292)
      - Sturges, Catherine Vesta to Juan Montoya, 1935 Nov 22 (Box 42, Folder 1293)
      - Tannenbaum, Frank to Max Eastman, 1915 May 19 (Box 42, Folder 1294)
      - Taos County Co-op Health Association to Henwar Rodiekiewicz, 1944 Mar 2 (Box 42, Folder 1295)
      - Torrence, Ridgely to "Paula", 1940 Feb 5 (Box 42, Folder 1296)
      - Waters, "Janey" to Mrs. Walter Clark, 1946 Aug 28 (Box 42, Folder 1297)
      - Wells, Margaret to Witter Bynner, 1922 Jul 3 (Box 42, Folder 1298)
      - "Lincoln" to "Dan", 1915 Dec 11 (Box 42, Folder 1299)
      - "Naomi" to "Janey" [Waters?], n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1300)
      - "Westie" to "Smudge" [Draper?], 1926 (Box 42, Folder 1301)
      - Unidentified to "Mr. Hastings", 1917 Aug 3 (Box 42, Folder 1302)
      - Unidentified to "Dr. Karl", 1940 Jan 19 (Box 42, Folder 1303)
      - Unidentified to Moni Moulik, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1304)
      - Unidentified to [Carissa?], n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1305)
- Writings, 1910-1953; Series II; 8.76; (21 boxes)
  Series II, Writings, is organized into twelve subseries and arranged alphabetically within each subseries by title or author.
  - ARTICLES AND ESSAYS
    - "Alas! The Idols..."
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1306)
      - Typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1307)
    - "All Cultures," typescript, corrected, 1938 Aug (Box 43, Folder 1308)
    - "The Apparent and the Real," printed version, El Crepusculo, 1949 Jun 23 (Box 43, Folder 1309)
    - "The Art of Georgia O'Keeffe," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1310)
    - "Aspen," printed version, [ El Crepusculo ?], 1949 Jul 14 (Box 43, Folder 1311)
    - "August," printed version, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1312)
    - "Awa Tsireh," printed version, The Arts, 1927 Jun (Box 43, Folder 1313)
    - "Bach in the Baggage Car"
      - Typescript, corrected, 1936 May 11 (Box 43, Folder 1314)
      - Typescript carbon, corrected, 1936 May 11 (Box 43, Folder 1315)
    - "A Beating Heart, a Symbol of Humanity," printed version, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1316)
    - "Business--As Usual!" printed version, El Crepusculo, 1949 Jun 9 (Box 43, Folder 1317)
    - "Canned Music..." printed version, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1318)
    - "Change of Life"
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1319)
      - Typescript, 1938 Aug (Box 43, Folder 1320)
    - "Chinese Coats," typescript, corrected, 1916-17 (Box 43, Folder 1321)